<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
    <feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <title>Gabriele's Pixelated Corner</title>
        <subtitle>A pixelated, personal corner on the web belonging to an aspiring game developer named Gabriele Corti.</subtitle>
        <link href="https://borntofrappe.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" />
        <link href="https://borntofrappe.github.io" />
        <updated>2023-01-22T21:14:13.893Z</updated>
        <id>https://borntofrappe.github.io/</id>
        <author>
        <name>Gabriele Corti</name>
        <email>borntofrappe@gmail.com</email>
        </author>
        
            <entry>
                <title>Pixel Art</title>
                <link href="https://borntofrappe.github.io/pixel-art"/>
                <id>https://borntofrappe.github.io/pixel-art/</id>
                <updated>2023-01-22T21:46:43.000Z</updated>
                <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I decided to create a folder in the repository housing this very website. A directory purposed for, surpise surpise, <a href="https://github.com/borntofrappe/borntofrappe.github.io/tree/main/pixel-art">pixel art</a>. The first assets have quite a distinct appeal — you might have guessed it by the style of the entire app.</p>
<p>I am particularly proud of three of them, combined and animated in a nice long strip. Unfortunately, you'll spot the visual only if you go looking for a page that does not exist. The irony. Just for once, however, I'll tip you to it. Here's a spiffy <a href="https://borntofrappe.github.io/404.html">404 page</a>.</p>
]]></content>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <title>Taking a break</title>
                <link href="https://borntofrappe.github.io/taking-a-break"/>
                <id>https://borntofrappe.github.io/taking-a-break/</id>
                <updated>2023-01-15T21:23:00.000Z</updated>
                <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After just one entry this log takes a break. A scheduled break, bound to end in five to six days. For a very simple reason, explained in a very convoluted manner.</p>
<h2>How this website was built</h2>
<p><a href="/hello-world">In the first post</a> I mentioned the stack behind the website:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>the build tool <a href="https://kit.svelte.dev/">SvelteKit</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>the hosting service <a href="https://pages.github.com/">GitHub Pages</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>You could discuss down the node packages and highlight further:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><code>gray-matter</code> to parse YAML front matter</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><code>markdown-it</code> to parse markdown into browser-friendly HTML</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><code>shiki</code> to highlight code fences</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Why the shopping list? For a very simple reason: I do not plan to write about the topic any further.</p>
<p>This application has a landing page and a blog-like section. Fingers crossed, they both work.</p>
<p>How the application works is beside the point. You will be thankful if you care about the actual topic, much less so if you were really interested in a detailed write-up of data fetching and Svelte syntax. At least you got a deluge of technical information early on, and a reason to stop reading already.</p>
<h2>What is the point of this website</h2>
<p>Games.</p>
<p>Playing games, making games, learning how to make, and how to play?, games.</p>
<p>I first approached game development with <a href="https://cs50.harvard.edu/games/2018/">CS50 intro to game development</a>, creating clones of 2D games as well as my little own experiments <a href="https://github.com/borntofrappe/game-development">with Lua and Love2D</a>.</p>
<p>It is a topic which honestly fascinates me, a topic which unfortunately fell out of rotation as I started working on &quot;more serious&quot; applications, and a topic I plan to cover deliberately over the weekend.</p>
<p>Hence, this entry.</p>
<p>Therefore, the break.</p>
<p>It is currently 22.41 of a chilly Sunday, and while I'm slowly, dangerously approaching the point of breaking the premise, I commit to a new article next Saturday, most likely with something more interesting to say. Perhaps with even something more entertaining to share.</p>
]]></content>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <title>Hello world</title>
                <link href="https://borntofrappe.github.io/hello-world"/>
                <id>https://borntofrappe.github.io/hello-world/</id>
                <updated>2023-01-15T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
                <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you are reading this introductory post, it means this enterprise is already a success. It means I did manage to deploy a static website on <a href="https://pages.github.com/">GitHub Pages</a>. An application built with <a href="https://kit.svelte.dev/">SvelteKit</a>, with a spiffy landing page and a blog.</p>
<p>That's all? In more ways than one, it currently is.</p>
]]></content>
            </entry>
    </feed>